A Shinobi of the Leaf
（カカシ）立て。
Stand up!
行くぞ。
We're leaving.
What about the mission, Kakashi?
（甲）任務はどうするんですか？
カカシさん。
ここを調べるっていう任務は。
Our mission is to search this location.
（カカシ）お前のせいで中断だ。
It's suspended, because of you.
Don't let me stop you.
（甲）僕のことならお構いなく。
俺の命を狙っておきながら
ふざけるな。
You're trying to kill me,
so stop joking around.
I'm not joking around.
ふざけてなんかいませんが。
Move!
行け！
I hear Foundation agents
are all trained
根の者は　一切の感情を捨てろと
教えられるらしいが→
to discard their emotions.
Does the same go for you?
お前もか？
Not just our emotions.
感情だけではありません。
名も過去も未来も捨て
任務のために尽くすんです。
Shinobi of the Foundation
have no names, no past, no future.
We have only our missions.
お前の任務は失敗だ。
Well, you failed your mission.
そこを動くな！
Don't move!
（甲）うわ～！
蛇？
Snakes?
What are they?
何です？　コイツら。
That one too!
アイツも！
ただの蛇じゃない。
大蛇丸の実験体か？
They're not ordinary snakes!
They're Orochimaru's experiments.
なに！
What?!
甲！
Kinoe!
うお～！
《甲：死んだ。
Dead.
Everyone's dead.
みんな　死んだ。
僕も死ぬんだ　ここで　このまま。
I'm going to die too…
In here, like this…
I don't want to…
いやだ…》
生きてるか？
Are you alive?
大丈夫か？　甲。
Are you all right, Kinoe?!
Are you all right?
大丈夫か？
I think so… But why?
なんとか…。　でも　どうして？
何が？
僕を助けた。
Why what?
Why did you save me?
見殺しにできるか。
I couldn't just let you die.
見殺しにしても
おかしくない相手でしょう　僕は。
But even if you did,
I would have deserved it.
お前　死にたかったのか？
Did you…want to die?
いえ　死にたくはありません。
No, I didn't.
僕は
死にたくはありませんでした。
I…did not want to die.
だったら
生きてることに感謝しろ。
Then be thankful that you're alive.
That…I'm alive?
生きてることに　ですか？
蛇の体液が…。
The fluid from the snake…
これは！
This is…
吸うな！　毒だ　走れ！
Don't inhale! It's poisonous! Run!
はい！
R-Right!
カカシさん！
Kakashi!
((カカシ：俺は
大蛇丸に会わなかった。
I didn't encounter Orochimaru.
奇妙な一族にも。
Nor did I encounter a strange clan…
そして　根の者にもな。
Nor someone from the Foundation.
《僕は
掟の中でしか生きられない。
I can only live by the rules.
でも　それでいい。
But that's okay.
誰かを守ることができるって
わかったから》
I know now that I'm capable
of protecting someone.
(（ダンゾウ）わしの　この眼の代わりを
手に入れてこい))
Get me a replacement for
this right eye of mine.
甲　カカシは？
Kinoe, where's Kakashi?
やったか。
はい。
You did it?
Yes.
俺の出番はなかったな。
So you didn't need me.
死体は？
Where's his body?
大蛇丸のトラップにやられたように
見せかけてあります。
I made it appear like he was killed
by Orochimaru's trap.
火影の暗部が見つけるでしょう。
Lord Hokage's ANBU
will probably find him.
よし　尻尾をつかまれないうちに
戻ろう。
Good. Let's return before
they get wind of us.
甲！
Kinoe?
（甲）「カカシさんへ。
To Kakashi…
僕には　味方を殺すという→
I've become confused
about this mission,
この任務の意味が
わからなくなりました。
where I'm supposed to kill a friend.
だから　任務を放棄します。
So I'm going to abandon
this mission,
ダンゾウ様には　任務に失敗したと
伝えます。
and I will report to Lord Danzo
that I failed.
カカシさんは　ご自愛ください」。
Please take care.
甲…。
Kinoe…!
（夕顔）カカシ先輩　まだ治療を…。
（カカシ）報告が先だ！
Kakashi Senpai, we have to
tend to your wounds.
I must report in first!
Hmm?
どうした？
What's the matter?
三代目　根の木遁使いの件です。
Lord Third…
Regarding the Foundation's
Wood Style user…
俺は　アイツに命を狙われました。
He targeted me.
ダンゾウ様の命令でしょう。
Lord Danzo ordered it.
ですが　アイツは　命令に逆らい→
But he dropped his mission midway
and saved my life.
途中で任務を放棄し
俺を助けてくれました。
里に戻ったようですが→
He then returned to the village.
今頃どうなっているか
わかりません。
But who knows what's happened
to him by now.
これは　どういうことだ？　甲。
W-What is the meaning of this, Kinoe!
申し訳ありません
任務に失敗しました。
I beg your pardon.
I failed my mission.
（ダンゾウ）カカシに返り討ちにあった
というならば→
If Kakashi beat you,
任務に送り出した　わしの失敗だ。
then it's my fault
for underestimating Kakashi's strength.
わしが　カカシの力を
見誤ったのだからな。
だが　お前は　このような小細工で
乙をはかり→
However, you abandoned
your mission
and did a poor job of faking his death,
and then returned here…
任務を放棄して
おめおめと戻ってきた。
２人がかりで
カカシを倒せばよいものを！
And I sent two men to do the job!
どういうつもりだ？
What was your intention?
答えよ　どういうつもりなのだ？
Answer me.
Why did you do this?
ダンゾウ様にかけあって
甲を助けてください。
Please go to Lord Danzo
and save Kinoe.
はぁ…。
三代目！
Lord Third!
根には　わしも　口を
出さぬことにしておるのだがな。
It's agreed upon that
I don't interfere with the Foundation.
さすがに　これは　そうもいかん。
However, that is not possible
in this case.
夕顔よ。
（夕顔）はっ！
Yugao.
Sir!
この書状を持って根の本部へ行け。
Take this missive
to Foundation headquarters.
火影よりの命令だ。
It's an order from the Hokage.
ダンゾウに今すぐここに
来るようにとな。
Summon Danzo here immediately.
はっ！
Yes, sir!
頼んだぞ　夕顔。
I'm counting on you, Yugao.
お任せください。
Please rest assured, my lord.
カカシ。
はっ！
Kakashi…
Sir.
お前は　医療班へ行って
ケガの治療を。
Go to the infirmary and
tend to your wounds.
はっ！
Yes, sir.
先輩？
俺も行く。
Senpai?!
I'm coming with you.
（甲）カカシさんは木ノ葉の忍です。
Kakashi is a shinobi of the Leaf.
同じ木ノ葉の仲間です。
He is a Leaf comrade.
Is it right to kill a friend?
その仲間を殺して
いいのでしょうか？
Consider only those in
the Foundation your friends.
（ダンゾウ）お前の仲間と呼べるのは
同じ根の者たちだけだと思え。
根は
木ノ葉の仲間ではないのですか？
Isn't the Foundation
a friend of the Hidden Leaf?
The Foundation is
a unique organization that supports
根は木ノ葉という大木を→
目に見えぬ地の中より支える組織。
the large tree known as the Leaf,
from deep underground.
大木が地上と地下とに
分かれるように→
Just as a tree is divided into what is above
and below ground,
the Foundation has its own existence.
根は独自の存在なのだ。
乙　根の忍とは？
Kinoto… What is a Foundation shinobi?
根の忍は　名前はない。
Shinobi of the Foundation
have no names.
No emotion. No past. No future.
感情はない　過去はない
未来はない。
あるのは　任務のみ。
We have only our missions.
その根を束ねる
わしの任務は絶対なのだ。
As the leader of the Foundation,
my missions are absolute!
《未来はない　過去はない。
No future…
No past… No emotion?
感情は　ない？
名前は　ない？》
No name?
((ユキミ：おかえり　テンゾウ！))
Welcome back, Tenzo!
聞いているのか　甲！
Are you listening, Kinoe?!
違う
僕の名前は甲なんかじゃない！
No! My name is not Kinoe!
な　何を言う？
What are you saying?
お前は根の甲。
You are Kinoe of the Foundation.
そのかりそめの名以外に
何がある？
What other name could you have
besides that temporary one?
僕は木ノ葉の忍です。
I am a shinobi of the Leaf!
根だけじゃない。
Not just of the Foundation!
A shinobi of the Hidden Leaf,
which has a trunk and branches!
幹もあり枝もある
この木ノ葉の忍です。
みんなが仲間なんです！
Everyone is my comrade!
Damn you…
キサマ　何に心を乱された！
What made you turn on us?!
こやつを処置室へ運んでおけ！
Take him to the treatment room.
更なる呪印で縛る！
はっ！
Bind him with a Curse Mark.
Sir!
（夕顔）火影様より
ダンゾウ様への召喚命令だ。
Lord Third has summoned Lord Danzo.
ダンゾウ様は　ただちに→
Notify him that he is
to appear immediately.
火影様のもとへ出頭願いたしと
伝えよ。
ダンゾウ様は　ご不在だ。
なんだと？
SUMMON
Lord Danzo is not here.
What?
戻られしだい
召喚命令は　お伝えする。
We will let him know
as soon as he returns.
（カカシ）今　どこにいる？
Where is he now?
We do not know.
それは我らの知らぬこと。
我らにダンゾウ様の行動を
詮索などできぬ。
We aren't privy to Lord Danzo's schedule.
お前は戻って三代目に
これを伝えろ。
Go back and report this to Lord Third.
先輩は？
ここで帰りを待つ。
What about you?
I'll stay here and wait for him. Go.
行け！
はっ！
Right.
止まれ！
これよりは根の領域だ！
Stop!
You are under Foundation jurisdiction!
甲は　どこだ？
Where is Kinoe?
甲め　カカシに何を吹き込まれた…。
Damn Kinoe…
What crazy thoughts did
Kakashi put in his head?
ダンゾウ様　準備が整いました。
うむ。
Lord Danzo, we're ready.
解！
Release!
逃げるぞ。
カカシさん！？
Let's get out of here!
Kakashi?!
あっ　甲！
Kinoe!
木遁！
Wood Style!
おい　待て！
Hey, wait!
いたぞ　あそこだ！
Found him! Over there!
風遁　真空玉！
Wind Style:
Vacuum Bullets!
木遁　木錠壁！
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
お前のほうから　わざわざ
来てくれようとはな　カカシ。
How good of you to come over
from your side, Kakashi.
根の領域に許しなく立ち入り→
You entered Foundation jurisdiction
without authorization
根の忍を連れ出そうとしたのだ。
and tried to take one of our own.
ただで済むとは思っておるまい。
Don't think you'll get off so easily.
ダンゾウ様　カカシさんは…。
Lord Danzo, Kakashi is…
黙れ！
Silence!
お前も　ただで済むとは
思わぬことだ。
And you won't get away with this either.
お前もな！
Neither shall you…
ヒルゼン。
Hiruzen…
お前が　カカシを
恨んでいることは知っている。
I know that you bear
a grudge against Kakashi.
だが　そんなことで里の優秀な
忍を狙うのはやめてもらいたい。
But that's no cause to target
one of our best shinobi.
何のことだ　ヒルゼン？
What are you talking about, Hiruzen?
（ダンゾウ）わしは
カカシなど　どうでもよい。
I could care less about Kakashi.
だが　根の施設に
勝手に侵入したことは問題だ。
However, he trespassed
by his own accord,
into Foundation territory
and that is serious.
勝手に？　いや　わしは
お前に召喚命令を出したのだぞ。
"By his own accord"?
No, I dispatched him with
a summons from me.
それに対し　居留守を使った
お前を探しに入ったのだよ。
Then he went looking for you.
わしの命令で。
On my orders.
どこかで伝達違いが
あったようだな。
There must've been
a communication mix-up.
それは初めて聞いた。
I'm hearing that for the first time.
では　カカシの件は
これで片づいたとしよう。
Well then, that settles it
with Kakashi.
次の件を話すために
お前を召喚しようとしたのだ。
It's regarding this next issue
that I sent for you.
里のもう一人の優秀な忍のことだ。
It's regarding another
superior shinobi of this village.
木遁使いは木ノ葉の里の宿願で
あることを知っておるはず。
You know that the Wood Style user
has long been desired
in Hidden Leaf Village.
無理な実験をしてまで→
There even was a period when
we conducted tests to acquire that power.
その力を手に入れようとした
時代もあったな。
その木遁使いが　いながら→
Now I understand there
is such a Wood Style user.
根に隠しておいたのは
どういうことか？
Why would you keep him hidden
within the Foundation?
その者は　わしが発見し保護し
育てていたが→
I found him.
And I protected and raised him.
べつに隠していたわけではない。
It's not like I was hiding him.
報告の必要はないと判断したのだ。
I just felt there was no need
to report it to you.
のう　ダンゾウ。
Listen, Danzo.
人柱力の子も
もう４歳になった。
The Jinchuriki child is
now four years old.
木遁の封印術は里にとって
ますます重要だ。
The Wood Style Sealing Jutsu
is becoming
more and more crucial to the village.
そこでだ。
So…
わしに　この者を
預けてはくれぬか？
Will you entrust this user to me?
火影直轄の暗部に入れる。
I'll assign him to the ANBU
under my direct control.
しかし…。
But…
頼む　ダンゾウ。
Please, Danzo.
優秀な配下であろうが→
I know he is a valuable
subordinate to you.
木ノ葉のために
根から移してやってくれ。
But for the sake of the Hidden Leaf,
transfer him to me.
それで　すべては
何事もなく片づく。
Then all will be settled amicably…
根の者には　秘密を喋れぬよう
呪印が　ほどこしてある。
Members of the Foundation
have a Curse Mark,
so they do not
reveal top-secret intel.
その呪印は解かぬぞ。
I will not remove the Curse Mark.
構わぬ。
よし。
That is fine.
All right then…
では　譲り受ける。
I now receive him into my care.
これより　おぬしは
火影直轄の暗部の所属じゃ。
Henceforth, you will be an ANBU
under my direct orders.
あの…。
Umm…
お世話になりました。
Thank you for everything.
あ　あの　このたび根から
こちらへ転属になった甲です。
H-Hello…
I just transferred here from
the Foundation. I'm Kinoe.
よう　テンゾウ！
Hey, Tenzo!
テンゾウ？
Tenzo?
甲は根のコードネームだ。
Kinoe was your codename
in the Foundation.
暗部では　テンゾウを
名乗ったらいい。
In the ANBU,
you should call yourself Te
でも　その名前は…。
お前　昔　自分で
テンゾウって名乗ってなかったか？
よし　みんな　新しく
仲間になったテンゾウだ。
実力は俺が保証する。
よろしく！
よろしくな！
テンゾウ…　ですか。
テンゾウ　配属は俺の　ろ班だ。
よろしく頼むぞ。
はい　先輩！
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のあれよ
＜　その野菜とは…＞
＜　それは　日本人に
春の訪れを告げる旬の野菜＞